{
  "title": "General_Aptitude-_CSE - Verbal_Ability_–_CSE — Slot 4 (15 Questions)",
  "duration": 42,
  "sections": [
    {
      "name": "Verbal_Ability_–_CSE — Slot 4",
      "questions": [
        {
          "id": 1,
          "question": "<p>\"The hold of the nationalist imagination on our colonial past is such that anything inadequately or improperly nationalist is just not history.\"<br><br>\nWhich of the following statements best reflects the author's opinion? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Nationalists are highly imaginative.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>History is viewed through the filter of nationalism.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Our colonial past never happened.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Nationalism has to be both adequately and properly imagined.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>History is viewed through the filter of nationalism.</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118409/gate-cse-2017-set-1-question-ga-6#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 2,
          "question": "<p>Research in the workplace reveals that people work for many reasons _______________ . <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>money beside</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>beside money</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>money besides</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>besides money</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>besides money</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118405/gate-cse-2017-set-1-question-ga-2#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 3,
          "question": "<p>After Rajendra Chola returned from his voyage to Indonesia, he ________ to visit the temple in Thanjavur. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2017 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>was wishing</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>is wishing</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>wished</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>had wished</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>wished</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/118403/gate-cse-2017-set-1-question-ga-1#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 4,
          "question": "<p>All hill-stations have a lake. Ooty has two lakes.<br>\n<br>\nWhich of the statement(s) below is/are logically valid and can be inferred from the above sentences?\n<br><br>\n(i).   Ooty is not a hill-station.\n<br>(ii).  No hill-station can have more than one lake. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) only.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) only.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both (i) and (ii)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither (i) nor (ii)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither (i) nor (ii)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39534/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-08#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 5,
          "question": "<p>Computers were invented for performing only high-end useful computations. However, it is no understatement that they have taken over our world today. The internet, for example, is ubiquitous. Many believe that the internet itself is an unintended consequence of the original invention. With the advent of mobile computing on our phones, a whole new dimension is now enabled. One is left wondering if all these developments are good or, more importantly, required.<br><br>Which of the statement(s) below is/are logically valid and can be inferred from the above paragraph?<br>(i) The author believes that computers are not good for us.\n<br>\n(ii) Mobile computers and the internet are both intended inventions. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Both (i) and (ii)</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither (i) nor (ii)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Neither (i) nor (ii)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39533/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-07#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 6,
          "question": "<p>Pick the odd one from the following options. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>CADBE</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>JHKIL</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>XVYWZ</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>ONPMQ</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>ONPMQ</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39528/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-04#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 7,
          "question": "<p>Find the odd one in the following group of words.\n<br><br>\nmock, deride, praise, jeer <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Mock</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Deride</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Praise</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Jeer</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>Praise</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39530/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-03#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 8,
          "question": "<p>Nobody knows how the Indian cricket team is going to cope with the difficult and seamer-friendly wickets in Australia.\n<br><br>\nChoose the option which is closest in meaning to the underlined phrase in the above sentence. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>Put up with.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Put in with.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Put down to.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Put up against.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>Put up with.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39531/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-02#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 9,
          "question": "<p>The man who is now Municipal Commissioner worked as _____________ <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-2)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>the security guard at a university</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>a security guard at the university</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>a security guard at university</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>the security guard at the university</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>B.</b> <p>a security guard at the university</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39529/gate-cse-2016-set-2-question-ga-01#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 10,
          "question": "<p>Consider the following statements relating to the level of poker play of four players P, Q, R and S.<br><br>I.    P always beats Q<br>\nII.   R always beats S<br>\nIII.  S loses to P only sometimes.<br>\nIV.  R always loses to Q<br><br>\nWhich of the following can be logically inferred from the above statements?<br><br>(i).  P is likely to beat all the three other players\n<br>(ii).  S is the absolute worst player in the set <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>(i) only</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>(ii) only</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>(i) and (ii) only</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>neither (i) nor (ii)</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>neither (i) nor (ii)</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39617/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga08#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 11,
          "question": "<p>Indian currency notes show the denomination indicated in at least seventeen languages. If this is not an indication of the nation's diversity, nothing else is.\n<br><br>\nWhich of the following can be logically inferred from the above sentences? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>India is a country of exactly seventeen languages.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>Linguistic pluralism is the only indicator of a nation's diversity.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>Indian currency notes have sufficient space for all the Indian languages.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>Linguistic pluralism is strong evidence of India's diversity.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>Linguistic pluralism is strong evidence of India's diversity.</p>",
          "marks": 2,
          "negative_marks": 0.67,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39613/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga07#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 12,
          "question": "<p>If 'relftaga' means carefree, 'otaga' means careful and 'fertaga' means careless, which of the following could mean 'aftercare'? <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>zentaga</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>tagafer</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>tagazen</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>relffer</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>C.</b> <p>tagazen</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39609/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga04#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 13,
          "question": "<p>Archimedes said, \"Give me a lever long enough and a fulcrum on which to place it, and I will move the world.\"\n<br><br>\nThe sentence above is an example of a ____________ statement. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>figurative</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>collateral</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>literal</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>figurine</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>figurative</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39606/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga03#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 14,
          "question": "<p>rewording of something written or spoken is a __________. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>paraphrase</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>paradox</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>paradigm</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>paraffin</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>A.</b> <p>paraphrase</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39607/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga02#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        },
        {
          "id": 15,
          "question": "<p>Out of the following four sentences, select the most suitable sentence with respect to grammar and usage. <br><br><strong>(GATE CSE 2016 SET-1)</strong></p>",
          "type": "single",
          "options": [
            "<b>A.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister does not meet me.</p>",
            "<b>B.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister doesn't meet me.</p>",
            "<b>C.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister meet me.</p>",
            "<b>D.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister meets me.</p>"
          ],
          "correct_answer": "<b>D.</b> <p>I will not leave the place until the minister meets me.</p>",
          "marks": 1,
          "negative_marks": 0.33,
          "explanation": "<a href=\"https://gateoverflow.in/39608/gate-cse-2016-set-1-question-ga01#a_list\" target=\"_blank\" rel=\"noopener\">Click here for detail solution by gateoverflow</a>"
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}